saveyourinternet.eu 2018-07-04

# Privacy Policy - Save Your Internet

This policy is applicable to all personal data processed by the Save your Internet website, operated by [N-square Consulting](http://www.n-square.eu/) registered at Kreupelstraat 33, 1703 Dilbeek, Belgium. We strictly limit the processing of your personal information, and work only with other organisations who do the same.

Any subpoena or attempts by government agencies or private sector organisations to gain access to any information that you give us will be vigorously challenged.

Emails received through info(at)saveyourinternet(dot)eu are reviewed by one staff member and sent onwards when necessary to other staff members. Our current service provider is Godaddy for email and Fastlane for the server hosting.

We run a variety of open and closed mailing lists, and the membership of closed mailing lists are kept confidential, though this information is shared with our mail service providers for the purpose of list-management.

We do not have a back-up policy for our communications. Each employee, as he or she sees fit, may retain the content of specific communications that he or she receives and sends, but we endeavour to keep this information stored securely through the use of encrypted emails.

We do not solicit information on political and religious beliefs or medical information. When such sensitive personal information is provided to us through our email or postal address, we delete or anonymise this information as soon as possible.

Telephone calls received on our number are serviced by Telenet and are beyond our control. As a result, the traffic data for these calls may be retained in accordance with various laws and a voluntary code of practice for the retention of communications data.

 **Website:** We honour encrypted browsing (https) by default. Our website runs on a WordPress platform and certain plugins monitor usage patterns for security purposes (they are used to detect hacking attempts). 

The processing of web usage data on our website itself is kept to a minimum. Moreover, all data collected is anonymised, and we do not share it with third parties except as relates to the New Mode tools (see paragraph hereunder). In order to better serve our members, we may use cookies (we'll let you know when we do so and ask you if you're ok with it) and periodically analyze web logs. We may collect IP addresses to better understand where our traffic is coming from, and to provide customized services to users. 

**Tools:** The tools we use to contact your MEPs collect some data. This helps us understand how much each tool was used and know if there are problems with any of them. It also allows us to ensure that, in case of use of the email tool, any reply by a representative reaches you directly. The tools used on this website (email your MEP, tweet your MEP, call your MEP) use software provided by New Mode. 

New Mode's privacy policy can be acccessed [here](https://www.newmode.net/privacy). As not everything in this privacy policy relates to the tools themselves, it is worth noting that the tool uses Google fonts, Sendgrid for the email provision, Twilio for the calling tool and will ask for access to your Twitter account to allow the tweeting function to work. For the latter, please not ethat you can rescind this authorisation at any time in your Twitter account settings under the section 'Apps'.

 **Other websites:** We may also point from our website to other internet services that do use cookies. These services do not fall under our control and we advise you to familiarise yourself with the privacy policies and terms of service that apply to these third party services. This is particularly the case with multi-media services and social plugins.

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy or require any clarifications, please contact info[at]saveyourinternet[dot]eu
